Primary Domains and Aims of DFSS
Welcome to this segment back on Design for Six Sigma.
What we’re going to do is look at the various domains of Six Sigma
relative to Designing for Six Sigma, Managing for Six Sigma, and Processing for Six Sigma.
Believe it or not that's going to help us to understand Design for Six Sigma.
We’re going to look at it from two angles, the management angle and the technical angle.
Now, if I look first at management in Design for Six Sigma.
What's the goal here? It's concerned with the identification and validation
of risks that are attributable
to the configuration of a deliverable or process. Think about that.
That's what Design for Six Sigma is focused on.
The identification and validation of all the risks
that are attributable to the configuration of a deliverable or process.
Now, as we look at the tail area
Remember that distribution? As we look at this tail area, the area greater than the upper spec.
That is risk. That red area right there is risk.
It’s risk over here.
So, we are concerned with identifying and validating those kind of risks.
During the configuration. Not after it's been put out into the process of being made.
But we’re going to try to stop variation in its track during the design phase.
That's what Designing for Six Sigma is about.
Now, that doesn't matter whether we’re designing hardware, or designing a process,
designing a service or a transaction.
Because remember, the word design means to configure or to plan.
So, anytime you do planning, your designing.
And if your designing, you need to be reducing risks.
Think about it. In a project planning exercise, this is what we want to do.
We want to reduce risks.
So, that's what the DFSS is about from a management point of view.
From a technical point of view. Design for Six Sigma is concerned with
characterization and optimization of risks.
So, we know there's four phases, identify, characterize, optimize, validate,
that is the strategy of breakthrough.
We identify and validate here.
Identify and validate is a management activity.
Characterize and optimize is a technical activity.
So, we want to characterize and optimize the risks that are attributable to the configuration.
So, we first want to identify, characterize, optimize and validate the risks
during the design process. That's what Design for Six Sigma is all about.
Now Processing for Six Sigma, is identify and validate the risks
that's associated with the operation of a process.
Notice, this is configuration of a process.
And PFSS is about the operation of that process.
Then we characterize and optimize the risks that are associated with the operation.
So you see, PFSS is concerned with optimal operation
of a process
and DFSS is concerned with configuration.
The optimal configuration, versus operation.
So that is in essence, the domains of Six Sigma.
And how we can go about comparing those and what their purposes are.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.